Once upon a time...
...there was
an old-fashioned kingdom
bound by tradition.
Here, everyone had
a part to play,
and they played it
without question.
Little did they know,
their world was about to change.
But until it did, y'all...
this village
of hardworking citizens
moved to the same beat
day after day,
generation after generation.
♪ Rhythm, rhythm ♪
♪ Rhythm ♪
♪ Nation ♪
♪ Rhythm, rhythm ♪
♪ Rhythm ♪
♪ Nation ♪
♪ People of the world today ♪
♪ Are we looking
for a better way ♪
- ♪ Of life? ♪
- ♪ Sing! ♪
♪ We are a part
of the rhythm nation ♪
♪ We are a part of
the rhythm nation ♪
And over here
is where our story begins,
at the humble home
of a practical woman
named Vivian,
who was alone again
after the death
of her second husband.
♪ Looking for
a better way of life ♪
Vivian's daughters:
the obnoxious Malvolia
and the self-absorbed Narissa.
She cray.
- ♪ We are a part ♪
♪ We are a part
of the rhythm nation ♪
Um, yeah.
They can be a lot.
I'm winning!
Whee!
And down here,
in this dingy basement,
the stepdaughter, Ella.
Or, as her stepsisters
call her, Cinderella,
because her skin
was often besmirched by cinders
and her stepsisters
were not that clever.
Right now,
she's dreaming of a world
in which she can live her life
any way she wants.
Uh, watch it now. You about
to roll over on that...
...pin.
♪ Listen as your day unfolds ♪
♪ Challenge what
the future holds ♪
♪ Try and keep
your head up to the sky ♪
♪ Others, they may
cause you tears ♪
♪ Go ahead, release your fears ♪
♪ Stand up and be counted ♪
♪ 'Cause you won't
unless you try ♪
♪ You gotta be,
you gotta be bad ♪
♪ You gotta be bold,
you gotta be wiser ♪
♪ You gotta be hard,
you gotta be tough ♪
♪ You gotta be stronger ♪
♪ You gotta be cool,
you gotta be calm ♪
♪ Gotta keep it together ♪
♪ All I know, all I know ♪
♪ Love will save the day ♪
♪ We are a part
of the rhythm nation ♪
♪ Time asks no questions ♪
- ♪ It goes on without you ♪
- ♪ Without you ♪
♪ Leaving you behind
if you can't stand the pace ♪
- ♪ Can't stand the pace ♪
- ♪ The world keeps on spinning ♪
♪ Can't stop it if you try to ♪
♪ The best part is danger
staring you in the face ♪
♪ You gotta be bad,
you gotta be bold ♪
♪ You gotta be wiser ♪
♪ You gotta be hard,
you gotta be tough ♪
♪ You gotta be stronger ♪
♪ You gotta be cool,
you gotta be calm ♪
♪ Gotta keep it together ♪
♪ All I know, all I know ♪
♪ Love will save the day ♪
- Smashed it!
- Perfectamundo.
Take that, birds.
Good morning,
my beady-eyed friends.
You hungry?
- Oh, yeah.
- Nod your head, mates.
- All she hears is squeaks.
- Mm. Come to papa.
Ooh.
♪ You gotta be bad,
you gotta be bold ♪
♪ You gotta, gotta,
gotta be wiser ♪
♪ You gotta be hard,
you gotta be tough ♪
♪ You gotta, gotta,
gotta be stronger ♪
♪ You gotta be cool,
you gotta be calm ♪
♪ Gotta, gotta
keep it together ♪
♪ All I know, all I know ♪
♪ All I know, oh ♪
- ♪ You gotta be cool... ♪
- ♪ People of the world today ♪
♪ Are we looking for
a better way of life? ♪
- ♪ Sing! ♪
- ♪ And calm... ♪
♪ We are a part of
the rhythm nation ♪
- ♪ Sing! ♪
- ♪ Stay strong... ♪
♪ People of the world today,
are we looking for ♪
♪ A better way of life? ♪
♪ 'Cause we are a part ♪
♪ Of the rhythm nation ♪
- ♪ I'm dreaming ♪
- ♪ People of the world today ♪
♪ Are we looking for ♪
- ♪ A better way of life? ♪
- ♪ I'm dreaming ♪
- ♪ Of a better way ♪
- ♪ We are a part ♪
- ♪ Of the rhythm nation ♪
- ♪ A better way of life ♪
♪ People of the world today,
are we looking for ♪
- ♪ A better way of life? ♪
- ♪ Of life ♪
♪ 'Cause we are a part
of the rhythm nation ♪
♪ All I know, all I know ♪
♪ All I know,
all I know is love ♪
♪ Will save the day ♪
♪ Mmm. ♪
Unhappy with the tea,
Stepmother?
Imagine if you served such swill
to your future husband.
How long would it take
for him to abandon you?
To understand
just how worthless you are?
Learn from this
and never do it again.
I thought she was
rather hard on her.
- I thought she could've gone harder.
- Quiet.
Cinderella, now that
you're an orphan,
it's important for you
to remember that
it's only my love for
your father... rest his soul...
that stands between you
and a life on the street.
Yes, of course. And that's why
I'm so thankful for...
You could be so pretty...
if you took even a second
to comb that hair of yours.
Oh, you're in.
Good morning, Ella.
Mr. Cecil.
It's Mr. Cecil!
I'm curious...
do you really need that cane?
No, but chicks dig it.
- Oh.
- Vivian.
Thomas.
And all the girls.
Lucky Thomas.
There they go.
Freshly picked from the farm.
Parsnips, turnips, rutabagas.
The fleshiest fruit
of the earth.
Would you like to come in?
Yes... N-No.
No, no, not today. Yeah, I just
wanted to check in on you
and make sure that your, uh,
blossoming daughters
are, uh...
um, managing.
Makes my skin crawl.
- Mine, too.
- I'm into it.
All right, then.
Now I've got this mental image
to nourish me through the day,
I'll be going.
Ew.
Fortune has smiled
upon this house.
My daughters have a suitor.
You mean this daughter
has a suitor.
The others have
heartache and jealousy.
Oh, ha-ha-ha.
Yeah, no, I am not
a match for Thomas.
Well, you must make yourself
a match for someone.
Yes.
I understand, Stepmother.
Here comes our girl.
Oh, boy, she's got heavy feet.
Oh, I slept in that fabric.
Shh!
♪ Here I go again ♪
♪ I'm imagining
a world outside ♪
♪ Unlike the one I'm in ♪
♪ Daydreaming again ♪
♪ Of when I'll get a chance ♪
♪ There's a world
that understands ♪
♪ Where you don't hear
the whispers ♪
♪ In the room
you're walking in ♪
♪ Daydreaming again ♪
♪ All I need is a chance ♪
♪ When I feel my fear
staring at me ♪
♪ I tell it just wait and see,
I know who I'm gonna be ♪
♪ I know who I'm gonna be ♪
♪ The world's half asleep,
it's gonna wake up and see ♪
- Ooh.
- Ooh, nice.
♪ If it's a million to one ♪
♪ I'm gonna be that one ♪
♪ And if it's
a shot in the dark ♪
♪ I'm gonna be the sun ♪
♪ And I just can't afford
to be wrong ♪
♪ Even when I'm afraid ♪
♪ You're gonna know my name ♪
♪ Yeah, you're gonna
know my name ♪
♪ Mmm ♪
♪ I can barely sleep ♪
♪ 'Cause my heart
is always racing ♪
♪ Chasing, pacing
round the room ♪
♪ Living carefully ♪
♪ Is something
I don't wanna do ♪
♪ When I feel my fear
staring at me ♪
♪ I tell it just wait and see,
I know who I'm gonna be ♪
♪ I know who I'm gonna be ♪
♪ The world's half asleep ♪
♪ It's gonna wake up and see ♪
♪ If it's a million to one ♪
♪ I'm gonna be that one ♪
♪ And if it's
a shot in the dark ♪
♪ I'm gonna be the sun ♪
- ♪ And I just can't afford ♪
- Oh!
♪ To be wrong ♪
♪ Even when I'm afraid ♪
♪ You're gonna know my name ♪
♪ Yeah, you're gonna
know my name ♪
♪ And I can see her
now and then ♪
♪ The one I know
that I could be ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ I see her laughin' ♪
♪ 'Cause she knew
all along in her head ♪
♪ So when the light
is hard to see ♪
♪ She's telling me ♪
♪ If it's a million to one ♪
♪ I'm gonna be that one ♪
♪ And if it's
a shot in the dark ♪
♪ I'm gonna be the sun, and I ♪
♪ I just can't afford ♪
- ♪ To be wrong ♪
- ♪ No, no, no, no, no, no, no ♪
- ♪ Even when I'm afraid ♪
- ♪ Not even when I'm afraid ♪
♪ You're gonna know my name ♪
- ♪ You're gonna know my name ♪
- ♪ Oh ♪
♪ You're gonna know my name ♪
♪ You're gonna
know my name, yeah ♪
♪ You're gonna know my name ♪
♪ You're gonna
know my name. ♪
God.
That's disgusting.
Well, thank you for coming in.
Well, before your aide-de-camp
loses a hand...
This is called a world map.
Now, take a look
at this blob here and here.
If we marry,
our blobs would join up,
and we would control the world
all the way
to this huge sea monster.
Mm, the sea monster.
You know, I really just
don't have the time
in my schedule
to be controlling
these far-off lands.
I am just too busy.
Doing what?
You spent three whole days
drinking and foxhunting.
That was a lot of hard work.
Now, you try tracking a fox
when drunk.
- It's impossible.
- No, it isn't!
You didn't.
Do not hit me, sweet prince!
No, no, no, no!
I promise, milord,
you can keep gallivanting here
with your merry bros,
and I'll have other interests.
We never have to be together,
except for royal events,
war planning
and when we have to engage
in the disgusting practice
of making a son.
Yeah?
Your offer is intriguing,
but I have no intention
on settling down anytime soon.
I see.
He's not working
with much upstairs,
and I'd be surprised
if it was different elsewhere.
She knows what I'm talking about.
♪ Hear ye, hear ye, hear ye ♪
♪ Hey, hear ye, uh ♪
♪ I'm the new town crier,
yeah, I took over from Barry ♪
♪ I know we all miss him,
but he died of dysentery ♪
♪ So now I'm here with
the announcements of the day ♪
♪ Got my band beside me, I know
you like the way they play ♪
♪ Today we got news
for you ladies and gents ♪
♪ A changing of the guard
is soon gonna commence ♪
♪ But this one is special,
better than the shire fair ♪
♪ 'Cause this time the whole
royal family will be there ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ King Rowan, of course,
and our Queen Beatrice ♪
♪ In their fancy royal robes,
you don't wanna miss ♪
♪ Prince Robert with the hair,
Princess Gwen, no doubt ♪
♪ See the new guards come in
and the old roll out ♪
♪ Yeah. ♪
Are they rosy yet?
The pain is quite terrific.
Ladies, are we ready?
What in God's name
are you doing?
Bringing color to her cheeks.
Good idea.
- Where's Cinderella?
- She's still in that basement.
- Cinderella!
- I'm starting to think she doesn't like us.
Cinderella!
Girls, can you help me?
- Cinderella!
You called?
Yes, stepchild.
Don't be dense.
I'm sorry, I-I was just...
About to make an excuse?
I could truly care less.
Grab your things.
Try not to make us late.
The changing of the guard
waits for no one.
Cinderella?
Yeah?
Do you think I look pretty?
I think you look so pretty.
But...
honestly, who cares
what I think?
Who cares what anyone thinks?
What matters is how you feel
when you look in the mirror.
That's deep.
How do I feel...
about myself?
Uh...
Yeah, I do.
I feel pretty.
Cool.
You have dirt on your face.
Please, girls,
we're going to be late.
What is that?
It's a dress.
I made it.
- Why?
- I don't know.
I-I just thought,
since the whole kingdom
will be there today,
I could find someone
who will maybe buy it.
To think that any girl,
let alone you,
would have the audacity
to engage
in matters of business,
it's insane.
I will not have you
embarrassing this household
with your blasphemy.
Don't ever let me catch you
trying such nonsense again.
Put the dress down.
Yes, Stepmother.
Good.
Now... shoulders back.
No slouching.
And smile.
Every girl is worth more
when she smiles.
What are you doing?
I am stewing in my own anger.
Oh, okay.
You turned down the daughter
of Lord Reginald.
I guess she wasn't the one.
She was!
I would've had control
of all the territories
right up to the domain
of the sea monster.
Well, perhaps you should marry
the sea monster, Robert.
I would have to have
grandmother's ring resized.
You keep overlooking
his behavior,
- and he'll never grow out of it.
- Stop.
He's gonna make a fine king.
Is it me,
or is your throne
just a little bit taller
than it was yesterday?
- I mean, it really looks...
- Oh, don't be ridiculous.
- Quite a bit.
- And even if it is,
I have every right
to make it taller.
I'm king.
Mm. Yes.
And I am ridiculous.
If you need me,
I shall be in my chambers.
Brushing my hair.
Until it all falls out.
So we good?
'Cause I got a thing.
Uh-uh-uh-uh-uh-uh-uh-uh.
You're bringing shame
on this family, Robert.
Have you seen this?
"The Roundabout Players
present The King's Idiot Son."
Ooh, do you think
we can still get tickets?
I'm becoming a laughingstock.
I think you're overreacting.
Well, why don't you ask
the Roundabout Players
if I'm overreacting?
They are currently
in a dark windowless room
under the castle.
You can't leave actors alone
in a basement without attention.
They'll die!
When you marry,
you'll settle down.
You'll stop behaving
like my idiot son,
and the perception
of the people will be
that you take the crown
seriously.
You can't control me.
Oh, that's exactly
what I can do.
That's the perk
of being the king.
But I feel nothing
for these women.
It's crazy to think
I'm actually gonna
fall in love with one of them.
Kings marry for power,
not for love.
Oh, well, it's perfect then
that Mother came with
three castles
and a hundred horses,
or I suppose
I never would've been born!
Silence!
Don't talk about
what you don't understand. Hmm?
Continue to defy me,
and just out of spite,
I'll give it all... the crown,
the palace,
everything... to your sister.
♪ Bum-bum-bum ♪
Leave us, Gwen.
Sorry.
I would be embarrassed
if I wasn't so bored
with my life.
But since I'm here,
I would love to stay
and help sort out
this whole crown issue.
You've been excused, Gwen.
Right.
But would this be a good time
for me to mention
how the kingdom could use
the power of the wind
- instead of burning filthy coal?
- Go!
Father, you know how badly
I want to be king.
I do.
Now, to make sure your nuptials
are done properly and on my
schedule, we shall hold a ball.
- ♪ A ball? ♪
- No.
♪ Balls are fun ♪
Yes. We'll invite
every woman of worth.
You'll dance.
You'll be charming.
You shall find a bride.
- Hmm?
- No, no, no.
D-Dancing at these things
is so... mannered.
And formal.
We look like fools!
Of course we do.
But women love it.
Good God, Robert,
if a rich man ever lost a woman,
it was to a man who could dance.
Why do I have to explain
everything to you?
This is insane!
I can't just pick
some bride at a ball.
And then what?
We're-we're supposed
to grow old together?
Into our 40s?
I mean, what are we even
gonna talk about?
You will go to the ball.
You will find someone.
That's an order.
Now, go dress.
I expect you to look sharp for
the changing of the guard. Hmm?
Nothing?
♪ A ball was a good idea ♪
Don't be late.
"Don't be late."
Well?
You heard the king.
♪ Can anybody ♪
♪ Find me ♪
♪ Somebody to ♪
♪ Love ♪
♪ Each morning I get up,
I die a little ♪ - ♪ Oh ♪
- ♪ Can barely stand on my feet ♪
- ♪ Ah ♪
♪ Take a look at yourself ♪
♪ Take a look
in the mirror and cry ♪
♪ And cry ♪ - ♪ Lord,
what you're doing to me ♪
- ♪ Yeah ♪
- ♪ I have spent all my years ♪
♪ In believing you ♪
♪ But I just can't
get no relief ♪
♪ Lord ♪
- ♪ Somebody, somebody ♪
♪ Can anybody find me ♪
♪ Somebody to love? ♪
- ♪ I work hard ♪
- ♪ He works hard ♪
♪ Every day of my life ♪
♪ I work till I ache
in my bones ♪
- ♪ Till he aches in his bones ♪
- ♪ But at the end of the day ♪
- ♪ At the end ♪
- ♪ I'm all on my own ♪
- ♪ He's on his ♪
- ♪ I get down on my knees ♪
- ♪ And I start to pray ♪
- ♪ Praise the Lord ♪
♪ Till the tears run down
from my eyes, Lord ♪
- ♪ Somebody, somebody ♪
♪ Can anybody find me ♪
- ♪ Somebody to love? ♪
- ♪ Somebody, somebody ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
- ♪ I work hard ♪
- ♪ He works hard ♪
- ♪ Every day of my life ♪
- ♪ Every day ♪
- ♪ I try and I try and I try ♪
- ♪ Try, try, try ♪
♪ But everybody wants
to put me down ♪
- ♪ They say I'm going crazy ♪
- ♪ He's going crazy ♪
♪ They say I got a lot
of water in my brain ♪
♪ I got no common sense ♪
♪ I got nobody left to believe ♪
♪ Find me somebody to love ♪
♪ Find me somebody
to love ♪
- ♪ Find me ♪
- ♪ Find me somebody ♪
- ♪ Somebody to love ♪
- ♪ Find me ♪
- ♪ Find me somebody ♪
- ♪ Somebody to love ♪
- ♪ Oh ♪
- ♪ Find me somebody ♪
- ♪ Somebody to love ♪
- ♪ Oh ♪
- ♪ Find me somebody ♪
- ♪ Somebody to love ♪
- ♪ Oh ♪
- ♪ Find me somebody ♪
- ♪ Somebody to love ♪
- ♪ Love, love, love, love ♪
- ♪ Oh ♪
- ♪ Somebody, somebody ♪
- ♪ Somebody ♪
- ♪ Anyone ♪
- Dude.
- ♪ Anybody ♪
♪ Can anybody find me ♪
♪ Somebody to... ♪
Get off my dad!
Oh, good.
Everyone's staring at me,
just as I'd hoped.
I'm sorry, Your Highness!
It's just really hard
to see in the back.
Might I suggest you put
some bleachers back there?
Give us short peasants a chance?
"I hereby decree
all short peasants
shall be pardoned by the king."
Get down now!
He doesn't... He didn't think
that was funny, did he?
Oop, bird poo.
♪ To love ♪
♪ Find me ♪
- ♪ Somebody find me ♪
- Excuse me, sorry.
♪ Find me, find me ♪
♪ Somebody, somebody find me ♪
♪ Someone to ♪
♪ Find me, find me ♪
♪ Find me ♪
♪ Someone to love. ♪
I'll play your silly game,
but only if every girl in the
kingdom is invited to the ball,
regardless of wealth or stature.
Marrying a commoner
is not at all what I meant.
Father, please.
Deep down,
you need me to be king.
What a black mark
it'll be on your name
if I don't continue the line.
So, what option
do you really have?
Too subtle?
Not subtle enough?
Fine.
So it shall be.
Don't even think about it, Gwen.
You're literally
not even going to let me
have a seat at the table?
I don't make up the rules.
I'm just the king.
Right.
So you're just going to
wander about until you find her,
wearing that
ridiculous disguise?
It works, Wilbur.
Nobody recognizes me.
Lucky for you.
Ah, no, too much.
What? The-the makeup?
- No, you look like a pirate.
- You look like a pirate.
Unnecessary.
You know, I can't believe
that you're willing to sully
the dignity of the royal family
for some commoner.
Wilbur, you sound old.
- I'm just...
- Just what?
She's-she's beautiful.
She's witty. She's fearless.
I mean, holy hell, did you see
the way she talked to my father?
- So mouthy.
- And glorious.
I must know her.
So, yes, I'm gonna
walk the streets
until I find her,
reveal my true self,
and then personally
invite her to the ball.
Unless, of course, it turns out
that she's got a couple bats
in the old belfry,
in which case, I will realize
that my feelings were incorrect
and...
slowly back away.
It is your belfry that has bats.
I do not have a single bat
in my belfry.
No, there are multiple bats
in your belfry.
I am the prince, and I say
that your belfry
is the one with the bats.
Well, I'm the prince's
best friend,
and I say that yours
is one with the bats.
I'm your best friend, right?
I have lots of friends.
Of course you're my best friend.
Yeah, thought so.
Beautiful human.
Bats.
Look at that.
Wow.
You know, it's a good thing
Stepmother never
comes down here.
She does not approve of pets.
Or charity.
Or kindness of any sort, really.
And she'd definitely
stop you from doing
whatever it is you're doing
right now, which is beautiful.
And only a little bit gross.
A little bit? It's revolting.
She needs to throw that out.
- I don't mind it.
- All right.
Wish me luck.
Because life
outside this basement...
...starts right now.
Girls, it shouldn't be so hard.
But it is.
Work is always hard.
Why are we doing
Cinderella work?
Because I want you to see what
you're in for if you don't marry
a man of means, like Thomas.
Thomas.
He's quite the catch.
Too bad he hasn't
been back in days.
Well, if it's not Thomas,
then it will just have to be
some other man.
Like him?
No.
No, no, no, no, no.
Do not cast your eyes
on some farm boy.
In this life,
you must marry rich.
Get yourself a man
who can pay for everything,
and then you will never
so much as have to hang
your wet undergarments again.
- I'm-a go see if he needs a wife.
- No.
Farm boy is off the table.
No matter how toothsome
he may be, and...
...and toothsome he is.
Ew, what does that mean?
It's how old people
say "poppin'."
- Ah.
- You must always think
and act like this.
♪ Some boys kiss me,
some boys hug me ♪
♪ I think they're okay ♪
♪ If they don't give me
proper credit ♪
♪ I just walk away ♪
♪ They can beg ♪
♪ And they can plead ♪
♪ But they can't see the light ♪
♪ That's right ♪
♪ 'Cause the boy
with the cold, hard cash ♪
♪ Is always Mr. Right ♪
♪ 'Cause we are living
in a material world ♪
♪ And I am a material girl ♪
♪ You know that we are living ♪
♪ In a material world ♪
♪ And I am a material girl ♪
But what about romance?
Oh, please.
Listen up.
♪ Some boys romance ♪
♪ Some boys slow dance ♪
♪ That's all right with me ♪
♪ If they can't
raise my interest ♪
♪ Then I have to let them be ♪
- ♪ Some boys try ♪
- ♪ Ooh... ♪
♪ And some boys lie ♪
- ♪ But I don't let them play ♪
- ♪ No way ♪
♪ Only boys
who save their pennies ♪
♪ Make my rainy day ♪
♪ 'Cause they are living
in a material world ♪
♪ And I am a material girl ♪
- Get it?
- Yes!
♪ We are living
in a material world ♪
♪ And I am a material girl ♪
♪ 'Cause everybody's living
in a material world ♪
♪ And I am a material girl... ♪
♪ 'Cause we are living
in a material world ♪
♪ And I am a material girl ♪
- ♪ You know, you know that ♪
- ♪ Material ♪
♪ I am a material girl ♪
- ♪ Living in a material world ♪
- ♪ Material ♪
♪ Living in a material ♪
♪ Ho, ho ♪
♪ Living in a material world ♪
♪ Material ♪
♪ Living in a ma... ♪
♪ Material world. ♪
"And Sons."
"Y Hermanos."
- Lovely day for a stroll.
- Mm-hmm.
I just adore your headpiece.
You know, it'd go beautifully
with this dress I made.
- I can give you a fair price.
- Shame on you.
Trying to sell me a dress
you clearly stole
from the lady you serve.
No, I-I stitched this
with my own two hands.
I should alert the king's guard
and have you arrested,
you street urchin.
Arrest...?
Okay.
Ladies and gentlemen!
For a mere
five pieces of silver,
who would like to purchase
this one-of-a-kind,
completely non-stolen dress?
Here's a laugh.
This girl fancies herself
a businessman.
Don't-Don't listen to him.
This is a one-of-a-kind design.
I'd stop while
you're ahead, missy.
- Who on earth do you think you are?
- Honestly.
But...
Sounds like you need
to lower your price.
Sir, please don't pile on, okay?
Not today.
No, no, I'm sorry.
It's a beautiful dress.
Right?
I should be allowed to sell it.
Sure, but women can't own shops.
- Uh-huh. And that's unfair.
- Is it?
Yes!
Us ladies give birth.
We run households.
Surely we can run a business.
Can't be that hard.
I mean,
wouldn't it just be great
if I could have my own shop?
Right here.
I could hang my garments
on that side.
And I'd say things like,
"Thank you. Come again."
Or, "Hot enough
out there for ya?"
What?
It's banter.
It breaks the ice.
Okay. What am I doing?
I'm going home.
- I'm talking to a stranger.
- I'll take it.
Take what?
The dress. I'll buy it.
Is this pity?
Are you doing this
'cause you feel sorry for me?
- Because that's really nice, but...
- No.
I'm just trying to do my part
to correct a flawed system.
What's your price?
I mean, the brooch alone...
Oh, the brooch.
That was my mother's.
I never knew her,
but I want to believe
she'd rather me have my dreams
than her brooch, so...
I'll pay triple
what you're asking.
You?
Don't judge a book
by its cover, milady.
♪ 'Ey! ♪
♪ Yeah, uh ♪
♪ Gather round, heed my call ♪
♪ In two weeks hence,
there'll be a ball ♪
♪ And not just any ball, this
night could change your life ♪
♪ See, it's time the prince
finally find his wife ♪
♪ That's right,
all the single ladies ♪
♪ Should be getting excited ♪
♪ Because every single one
to the ball is invited ♪
♪ So take a bath,
do your hair ♪ - Aw.
♪ Buy a fancy new dress,
paint your nails ♪
♪ You got a prince
to impress, yes ♪
♪ It's gonna be magic, yo, uh ♪
♪ So it'd be tragic, y'all, uh ♪
♪ If you were a sad chick,
yo, uh ♪
♪ And thought yourself
underqualified, nah ♪
♪ So put on a gown, y'all, uh ♪
♪ For a shot at the crown,
yo, uh ♪
♪ And prepare to get down,
y'all, uh ♪
♪ As Prince Robert ♪
♪ Chooses his bride. ♪
Prince Robert needs a ball
to find his bride.
What is wrong with him?
Maybe nothing's wrong with him.
I heard he just wants to allow
anyone the chance
to fall in love with him.
How conceited is that?
Rumors must be true.
What, pray tell, are the rumors?
You know, that he serves
no real function
other than to wreck things.
That the real brains
of the family is Princess Gwen.
Duh.
Oh, and that he's a mama's boy
who I heard, from time to time,
still gets spanked
on the tush-tush.
- Not true at all, though.
- Ah, maybe.
Sounds like a vicious lie to me.
So does this mean
you're not coming to the ball?
No way.
I mean, the whole thing
is weird and antiquated.
Not my thing.
Nice to meet you.
You know, we live in
a very old-fashioned kingdom,
but the ball, I mean,
there'll be guests there
from all over the world,
open-minded people
with cash to spare.
Now, I know them.
I can introduce you
if you'd like.
Why would you do that?
I mean, you just met me.
Let's just say
I know what it feels like
to not quite fit into the crate
you were born into.
And I... I believe in you.
Then, yes.
I'll go.
Huzzah!
What?
I heard a proper person say that
one time when he was excited.
Ah, look who's been around
a proper person.
Just once.
I once shared an apple
with a goat named King Rowan.
Well, I'm sure the prince
will definitely pick you.
I doubt it. I'm dirty.
I smell like a basement.
My best friends are mice.
It's a whole thing.
I-I will just find you
at the ball.
Thank you for this.
You're welcome.
Hope the dress fits!
Gonna try it on
as soon as I get home.
Okay.
He's kind of cute.
Give me your
finest fabrics, please, sir.
Yes!
This is it.
This is my chance.
Hmm.
♪ Am I wrong ♪
♪ For thinking out the box
from where I stay? ♪
♪ Am I wrong ♪
♪ For saying that
I'll choose another way? ♪
- ♪ Oh ♪
♪ I ain't trying to do
what everybody else doing ♪
♪ Just 'cause everybody doing
what they all do ♪
♪ If one thing I know,
how far would I grow? ♪
♪ I'm walking down
this road of mine ♪
♪ This road that I call home ♪
♪ So am I wrong ♪
♪ For thinking that
we could be something ♪
- ♪ For real? ♪
- ♪ Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Oh ♪ - ♪ No, no, no, no,
that's wrong ♪
♪ Now, am I wrong ♪
♪ For trying to reach
the things that I can't see? ♪
Ow!
- ♪ Oh, that's just how I feel ♪
- ♪ That's just how I feel ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
♪ That's just how I feel ♪
♪ Trying to reach the things
that I can't see ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
♪ Am I tripping? ♪
♪ Am I? ♪
♪ For having a vision? ♪
♪ My prediction ♪
♪ I'm-a be on top of the world ♪
- In your dreams!
- In your face!
- Girls, please!
- I assure you,
Robert will cease
to be a distraction.
♪ Hope you,
hope you don't look back ♪
♪ Always do what you decide ♪
♪ Don't let them
control your life ♪
- ♪ That's just how I feel ♪
- ♪ Whoa-oh-oh ♪
♪ Fight for yours
and don't let go ♪
♪ Don't let them
compare you, no ♪
♪ Don't worry,
you're not alone ♪
♪ That's just how I feel ♪
- ♪ That's just how we feel ♪
- ♪ That's just how I feel ♪
♪ If you tell me
I'm wrong, wrong ♪
♪ I don't wanna be
right, right ♪
♪ If you tell me
I'm wrong, wrong ♪
♪ I don't wanna be right ♪
- ♪ I don't wanna be right ♪
- ♪ Oh ♪
♪ If you tell me
I'm wrong, wrong ♪
♪ If you tell me I'm wrong ♪
♪ I don't wanna be
right, right ♪
- ♪ Right ♪
- ♪ If you tell me ♪
- ♪ I'm wrong, wrong ♪
- ♪ If you tell me I'm ♪
♪ Wrong, wrong ♪
♪ I don't wanna be right ♪
Thomas.
May I come in?
- ♪ Am I wrong? ♪
♪ For thinking that we could
be something for real? ♪
♪ Oh, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, oh ♪
- ♪ Now, am I wrong? ♪
- ♪ Am I wrong? ♪
- Not too fast.
- ♪ For trying to reach ♪
♪ The things that I can't see? ♪
♪ Oh, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, oh ♪
♪ That's just how I feel ♪
- ♪ How I feel, how I feel ♪
- ♪ Ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
- ♪ Yeah ♪
- ♪ That's just how I feel ♪
- ♪ How I feel ♪
♪ That's just how I feel ♪
♪ Trying to reach the things
that I can't see ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
♪ Am I wrong ♪
♪ For thinking that we could
be something for real? ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Now, am I wrong ♪
♪ For trying to reach
the things that I can't ♪
♪ See? ♪
Sorry, ma'am.
I feel great about myself.
All right, turn around.
Let me see.
Oh, my.
After tonight, one of you may
very well become a princess.
You really think so?
I do.
And after all the bad things
that have happened in our lives,
wouldn't it be nice
if we had something good?
It's over. I'm eating a muffin
and going to bed.
No.
Did you make that dress?
Mm-hmm.
I suppose it's nice.
It's tasteful.
Thank you.
I'm sorry, I should have said
something earlier,
but, Cinderella, you don't need
to go to the ball.
What do you mean?
Of course I do.
No, it's for girls
who are unbetrothed,
and as of this morning,
you are spoken for.
That's impossible.
I speak for me.
No, Thomas has expressed
his intentions to marry you.
Thomas?
But I don't want
to marry Thomas.
- I reject his intentions.
- Hush now.
Women who are promised away
do not go to balls.
Take off that dress
and go back to your basement.
No, but...
Please, Stepmother,
I have to go.
My future depends on it.
I-I spent weeks making
this dress so that I could
show women from
all over the world that I...
Why would you...?
Ow.
You are to stay home
and find a way
to be that man's bride.
Upset me further, and you will
have no one in this life.
Poor Ella.
She was so looking forward
to that ball.
- It's a shame.
- Absolutely devastating.
Uh, guys?
Gosh, that's beautiful.
What an improvement.
Adventure time.
Let's follow it.
Right behind you.
I really shouldn't run
on a full stomach, but okay.
♪ When I feel my fear
staring at me ♪
♪ I tell it just wait and see ♪
♪ I know who I'm gonna be ♪
♪ I know who I'm gonna ♪
♪ The world's half asleep ♪
♪ It's gonna wake up ♪
♪ And see... ♪
♪ If it's a million to one ♪
♪ I'm gonna be that one ♪
♪ And if it's
a shot in the dark ♪
♪ I'm gonna be the sun, and I ♪
♪ Just can't afford
to be wrong ♪
♪ Even when I'm afraid ♪
♪ You're gonna know my name ♪
♪ You're gonna know ♪
♪ My name, yeah ♪
♪ You're gonna know my name ♪
♪ You're gonna know my... ♪
You did it.
Well done, my friend.
Work! Yes!
Now, this is how
you make an entrance.
Allow me to introduce myself.
I am your Fabulous Godmother.
- But-but why?
- Baby, you saved me.
And so now I'm here to save you
by sending you to that ball.
Well, I'm not allowed
at the ball.
And, quite frankly,
I think you're a figment
of my imagination.
Okay, let's not ruin
this incredibly magical moment
with reason.
Do you want to go
to that ball and meet
a bunch of rich people
who will change your life?
Yes, I was just crying
and singing about it
like two minutes ago.
Okay, so that would be
an affirmative?
Yes.
I can't hear you.
- Yes!
- Like you mean it.
Yes!
Then go you shall.
♪ When you wish upon a star ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Your dreams will
take you very far ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ When you wish upon a dream ♪
♪ Hey, hey, oh ♪
♪ Life ain't always
what it seems ♪
♪ Sh-Sh-Sh-Shining star,
come into view ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Shine its watchful ♪
- ♪ Light on you ♪
- Ooh.
♪ You, you ♪
♪ Oh, give you strength
to carry on ♪
♪ Make your body
big and strong ♪
Uh...
You can't wear that to the ball.
I know.
Oh. Look at that.
This is... this is different.
- I've never seen anything like this.
- Okay, okay, dang.
You said you wanted
to be a businesswoman.
Think, Fab G, think.
Mm.
Did I miss...?
Wait...
for it.
Oh.
No, no, no, that design
is pure fantasy.
I don't even know
if it's possible.
Hush. It's magic time.
You know, the wind is
really picking up.
I feel like maybe we should
take this inside or...
♪ Shining star for you to see ♪
♪ What your life can truly be ♪
♪ What you can truly ♪
♪ Be... ♪
This is gorgeous!
Yas, future queen! Yas!
What's that, Prince?
You'd like to dance?
Ah-ah-ah.
Get in line, Your Highness.
Hold on.
Where am I going?
Wow.
They're beautiful.
They're glass?
Any way you can make 'em
more comfortable?
- No.
- But you're magic.
Women's shoes are as they are.
Even magic has its limits.
Oh.
Ow.
How am I gonna...?
Feet don't work like this.
Getting better.
Oh. Oh.
- I'm doing it.
- Oh!
♪ You're a shining star ♪
♪ No matter who you are ♪
♪ Shining bright to see ♪
♪ What you could truly be ♪
♪ You're a shining star ♪
♪ You know you're
a shining star ♪
♪ No matter who you are ♪
♪ No matter who you are, now ♪
- ♪ Shining bright to see ♪
- ♪ Yeah ♪
♪ What you could truly be. ♪
Go on with your bad self.
Oh, um, I don't suppose
you could actually get me
to the ball, could you?
- Ho...
- Ly...
Fudge.
You need footmen.
He sees us.
Well, well, well.
Look at you little
disgusting creatures.
You will do.
- Do for what?
- Yeah, do for what?
Do for what?!
- Whoa.
- Where's my tail?
I-I can't balance
without my tail.
You're boys?
I always assumed you were girls.
And why would you assume that?
Because everyone knows mice
are girls and rats are boys.
Well, how do you think
rats have more rats?
Moving away from that.
Now, the three of you are
going to make sure that
this beautiful young lady
gets to the ball.
We're going to the palace?
But we don't even know
where the palace is.
We've not been past
the front yard.
Well, except for that
one time when we had to leave
'cause snakes got
into the house.
- The what?
- Oh.
Yeah, no, we were gonna
tell you, but...
Okay, focus, people.
You are to make sure that
she gets to the ball,
and that is that.
♪ You're a shining star ♪
♪ No matter who you are ♪
♪ Shining bright to see ♪
♪ What you could truly be ♪
- ♪ Oh, oh ♪
- ♪ You're a shining star ♪
- ♪ Shining star ♪
- ♪ No matter who you are ♪
♪ Who you are, now ♪
- ♪ Shining bright to see ♪
- Tell 'em, Fab G.
- ♪ What you could truly be ♪
- ♪ Whoa... ♪
♪ You're a shining star ♪
- ♪ No matter who you are ♪
- ♪ Shining bright to see ♪
- ♪ See ♪
♪ What you could truly be ♪
♪ Oh, you're such
a shining star ♪
♪ You're a shining star ♪
- ♪ No matter who you are ♪
- ♪ Who you are ♪
♪ Shining bright to see ♪
♪ What you could truly be ♪
♪ You can truly be,
what you can truly be ♪
♪ Not you but me ♪
♪ Hey, yow! ♪
It's time to go.
Yep, yep.
We should... we should...
What am I doing?
My stepmother will disown me.
I mean, she'd throw me out
into the street.
She told me she would.
She told me she would do that.
Don't worry.
As long as you're in that gown,
no one will be able
to recognize you.
Actually, that's not good.
I'm meeting a stranger there
who's offered to help me.
My, my.
You are high-maintenance.
Fine.
He alone will be the exception.
But when the magic wears off...
Wait a second.
That's possible?
Nothing in life ever
stays the same,
good or bad.
Just remember...
when the clock
strikes midnight, run.
Hyah!
♪ You're a shining ♪
♪ Star... ♪
Are we really gonna
stay up here the whole night
like lifeless bunting?
You know how much
I love to dance.
Tonight is not about you.
It's about me.
And keeping an eye on our son.
Whether he shows up or not
remains to be seen.
Would this be a good time
for me to bring up
my comprehensive plan
to reduce poverty
- in the urban row housing?
- No, darling.
- Read the room.
- Never.
Ladies and gentlemen,
your prince!
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Ooh, yeah ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Uh ♪
♪ Hey ♪
♪ All right ♪
♪ What a man,
what a man, what a man ♪
♪ What a mighty good man ♪
♪ Gotta say it again, now ♪
♪ What a man,
what a man, what a man ♪
♪ What a mighty good man ♪
♪ He's a mighty,
mighty good man ♪
♪ What a man,
what a man, what a man ♪
♪ What a mighty good man ♪
♪ Yes, he is ♪
♪ What a man,
what a man, what a man ♪
- ♪ What a mighty good man ♪
- ♪ Yeah ♪
♪ I want to take
a minute or two ♪
♪ And give much respect due ♪
♪ To the man that's made
a difference in my world ♪
♪ And although
most men are hos ♪
♪ He flows on the down-low ♪
♪ 'Cause I never heard about him
with another girl ♪
♪ But I don't sweat it
because it's just pathetic ♪
♪ To let it get me involved in
that "he said, she said" crowd ♪
♪ I know that
ain't nobody perfect ♪
♪ I give props
to those who deserve it ♪
♪ And believe me, y'all,
he's worth it ♪
- ♪ Ooh ♪
- ♪ So here's to the future ♪
♪ 'Cause we got through
the past ♪
♪ I finally found somebody
that can make me laugh ♪
♪ You so crazy ♪
♪ I think I wanna
have your baby ♪
♪ Ow! ♪ - ♪ What a man,
what a man, what a man ♪
- ♪ What a mighty good man ♪
- ♪ All right ♪
♪ Yes, he is ♪
♪ What a man,
what a man, what a man ♪
♪ What a mighty good man ♪
♪ He's a mighty,
mighty good man ♪
♪ What a man,
what a man, what a man ♪
- ♪ Ooh ♪
- ♪ What a mighty good man ♪
♪ Gotta say it again, now ♪
♪ What a man,
what a man, what a man ♪
♪ What a mighty good man ♪
♪ Yes, he is, now ♪
♪ I'm gonna fight 'em off ♪
♪ A seven-nation army
couldn't hold me back ♪
♪ They're gonna rip it off ♪
♪ Taking their time
right behind my back ♪
♪ And I'm talking
to myself at night ♪
♪ Because I can't forget ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Back and forth
through my mind ♪
♪ Like a minuet ♪
♪ And the message coming from
my eyes says leave it alone ♪
♪ La, la-la-la-la ♪
♪ La, la ♪
♪ La-la-la-la ♪
♪ La, la-la-la-la ♪
♪ La, la ♪
♪ La-la-la-la ♪
♪ And if I catch it
coming back my way ♪
♪ I'm gonna serve it to you ♪
- ♪ La, la-la-la-la ♪
- ♪ What a man ♪
♪ La, la ♪ - ♪ What a man,
what a mighty good man ♪
- ♪ La, la-la-la-la ♪
- ♪ What a man, what a man ♪
♪ La-la-la-la ♪ - ♪ What a man,
what a mighty good man ♪
♪ And that ain't
what you want to hear ♪
♪ But that's what I'll do ♪
- ♪ La, la-la-la-la ♪
- ♪ What a man ♪
♪ La, la ♪ - ♪ What a man,
what a mighty good man ♪
♪ La, la-la-la-la ♪ - ♪ What
a man, what a man, what a man ♪
♪ What a mighty, mighty, mighty,
mighty, mighty good man ♪
- ♪ La, la-la-la-la ♪
- ♪ What a man, what a man ♪
- ♪ La, la ♪
- ♪ What a man ♪
- ♪ Oh ♪
- ♪ What a mighty good man ♪
♪ La, la-la-la-la, la-la-la-la ♪
♪ What a man. ♪
Did you see me?
I lifted her up!
Yeah. Yeah, I know. I know!
Where is she?
I'm so sorry.
I don't know
what I was thinking.
No, please, forgive me.
I'm not accustomed to being
among nobility, Your Grace.
Think nothing of it.
Tonight, we are all equals
in the eye of the king.
You're too kind.
My, what lovely shoes.
Yes. They're glass.
I could walk in them
easily after, like, four steps.
Now, uh, if you'll excuse me,
I was making my way
up to the balcony.
Because the best view
is always from on high.
Oh, my God.
Look at us. We're standing
outside the palace.
W-We're-we're literally
breathing the same air
as the royal family.
Whatever happens after tonight,
I'm a changed mouse.
- Mm-hmm.
- Guys!
I just relieved myself,
and you are not gonna believe
how it happens.
Through your front tail.
We know.
- Yes!
- Unbelievable, isn't it?
- Incredible, right?
- It's like...
You're-you're making me
want to go again right now.
You should go. Go now.
I would. Not got the urge.
I mean, could tonight
be any better?!
Excuse me, my dear.
May I ask you a question?
Yes, Your Highness.
"Your Highness" was the man
whose blood I spilled
to take this crown.
- Ooh.
- Call me Tatiana.
- Queen Tatiana.
- Of course.
Queen Tatiana.
Where did you get that dress?
It's so structured and yet
so delicate and-and...
and beautiful.
Me-me did. I...
It's-it's what I,
what-what I, what I done.
- What I, what I hope...
- I-I do...
I was... I-I did it.
I cou... I want to. I...
Good evening, ladies.
First, I would like to thank
each and every one of you
for being here.
You are all so beautiful
and have so much to offer.
But if I'm being honest,
there is only one
who has captured my attention.
Sadly, I have not
cast my eyes on her tonight.
Sorry. Words. Um...
I designed it.
Then I am honored
to be in the presence
of such an artist.
Would it be possible
to see more of your work?
- More than possible.
- Good.
I attend lavish events
around the world,
and I hate all my clothes.
I'm looking for someone
to travel with me
to enliven my wardrobe.
Maybe that person is you.
Me?
We will meet tomorrow
when the clock strikes 4:00.
I have an hour
before I catch my ship home.
Yes, yes. I'll be at the
south end of the market square.
Don't be late.
It's unlikely I'll return here,
and I have no patience
for those who misuse my time.
- Of course.
- After all,
I am a frickin' queen.
This is why
you save caterpillars.
A-And then she suggested
that I was a mama's boy
who still gets
a little spanking
on the tush-tush.
What?
Oh, now, now.
Don't act like you haven't
heard the rumors yourselves.
Look, I'm not ashamed
to admit that my mother
is a wonderful, strong woman.
We get along very well.
But not that well.
My father, on the other hand,
well, he-he's not exactly
getting any younger.
- Oh!
- Oh! -
I'm so sorry.
Oh, my God.
That didn't happen.
Didn't happen.
And even if it did happen,
I'm magic,
- so nobody can see me.
- Hi.
- You look, you look so different.
- Me different?
You're the one
who looks different!
All clean and...
That's a nice jacket.
Why would you let me speak
so poorly of you to your face?
I admit it was deceitful, but...
I mean, it worked. Here you are.
Yes, and I am leaving.
I've seen the dresses,
I drank the bubble drink,
and now I actually have a chance
to make my dreams come true.
So I'm gonna go.
I'm gonna go
while I'm still ahead.
Thank you.
Well, you haven't seen
all of the dresses.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I'd be remiss if I didn't take
a moment to acknowledge
someone truly special.
The people's princess,
my little sister.
Gwendolyn.
That's my dress.
That's-that's my dress
on the princess.
Are you all right?
I'm fine, I'm fine.
I just, uh...
I need you to stop the room
from spinning.
Perhaps this will work.
M-Maybe would you like to dance?
Right now?
♪ I found a love ♪
♪ For me ♪
♪ Darling, just dive right in ♪
♪ And follow my lead ♪
♪ Well, I found a boy ♪
♪ Beautiful and sweet ♪
♪ I never knew you were
the someone waiting for me ♪
♪ 'Cause we may be kids ♪
♪ But we're so in love ♪
♪ Fighting against all odds ♪
♪ I know we'll be all right ♪
♪ This time ♪
♪ Darling, just hold my hand ♪
♪ Be my girl ♪
- ♪ I'll be your man ♪
- ♪ Be my man ♪
♪ I see my future in your eyes ♪
♪ Baby, I'm ♪
♪ Dancing in the dark ♪
♪ With you between my arms ♪
♪ Barefoot on the grass ♪
♪ Listening to
our favorite song ♪
♪ When I saw you in that dress ♪
♪ Looking so beautiful ♪
♪ I don't deserve this ♪
♪ Darling, you look perfect ♪
♪ Baby, I'm ♪
♪ Dancing in the dark ♪
♪ With you between my arms ♪
♪ Barefoot on the grass ♪
♪ Listening to
our favorite song ♪
♪ I have faith in what I see ♪
♪ Now I know I have met
an angel in person ♪
♪ You look perfect ♪
- ♪ I don't deserve this ♪
♪ Tonight ♪
Would you care to talk
alone somewhere?
Lead the way.
What's it like being a crate?
Like, this has got to be
a step up, right?
- So this is the fountain.
- Ooh.
Do you have
a fountain where you live?
Um, I don't.
I just have
streaming water sometimes.
- What is that? What is that?
- Did you hear that? That.
- What?!
- This is bloody brilliant.
What even is that?
- We're just banging 'em together.
- I know.
Humans can be so loud.
- You make me nervous.
- Aw.
Everything about tonight
is insane, right?
B-Blink once
if you can understand me.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
- Thanks for the jacket.
No, it's not like
I'm cold or anything.
- Here we are.
- Wow.
It's beautiful.
Oh, um, I should probably
take my shoes off.
- Right?
- Oh, no, you're fine.
This floor is literally
2,000 years old.
- So no?
- You're fine.
Okay.
Oh, my God.
Are you gonna play something
on the piano just for me?
Oh, my God, you are.
Wow.
You're so full
of hidden talents.
So it sounds like you might
disagree with those who say
I "serve no real purpose
other than to wreck things"?
Just so you know,
I don't actually think
those things about you.
Especially now.
Well, you should.
Wh-Why?
I mean, you're in line
to be our future king.
Oh, it's a bad system.
My only qualification being
- that my dad was one.
- Mm.
It's not that
I don't want to be king.
When I was little,
I remember watching my father
go off to war
and thinking how...
brave he looked in his armor.
And I wanted to be
just like him.
And then, as I got older
and my life became
more about
traditions and customs
and people always watching me
and telling me what to do...
...and never asking
what I want or how I feel...
I know exactly what you mean.
What?
I just had...
no idea
tonight would go like this.
This is precisely
how I hoped tonight would go.
You're the one.
I pick you to be my princess.
What's wrong?
I-I assure you
it doesn't matter to me
that you're not of royal birth.
No, that's not it.
W-We'll get married.
Okay? We'll-we'll get married
and you will live the rest
of your life as royalty.
Royalty? What about my work?
M-My dresses can...
Well, that would
most likely be frowned upon.
Women have
a very prescribed role in court.
- "Prescribed role in court"?
- But I would make sure
that you were dressed by
the finest dressmakers
- in all the land.
- I'm a dressmaker.
I know. There's just
no one else in this world
I'd rather be with than you.
Robert, stop.
I don't want a life stuck
waving from a royal box
any more than a life
confined to a basement.
I have dreams
that I have to chase.
So if it's a choice...
...I choose me.
I understand.
Really, I... I do.
♪ I found a love ♪
♪ I found a boy ♪
I'm sorry.
What time is it?
It's midnight.
I have to go.
Wait!
I don't like this.
- Some-Something's changed.
- Relax. We are fine.
Ah!
You just cleaned
phantom whiskers.
- No, I did not.
- You did, too.
Where are you off to, my dear?
Am I to assume
I've lost you to the prince?
No, my queen. I'll meet you
tomorrow, I promise.
What's happening?
My good people,
your future queen.
Help.
This way. This way.
Wilbur.
Mm.
You go.
I'll take care of this.
Thank you so much.
I'll never forget this.
Neither will I.
The magic's wearing off.
- What are we gonna do?
- What did the butterfly say?
He called us disgusting,
that jerk.
About the magic.
What was said about the magic?
I don't know.
I was singing.
- Why didn't you pay attention?
- Because I was singing!
Ow, ow.
Dress your feet for comfort!
Get in.
Halt, I say!
Come on, quick!
- Get in! Quickly! Hurry!
- Come on!
Look. She threw
a glass shoe at me.
I-I feel all tingly.
Like I'm gonna...
Now I'm feeling tingly.
I don't want to go...
Don't look at me!
I'm starting
to feel a bit funny.
I feel tingly!
No!
Are we going down?
We're going down.
Just be quiet as a mouse.
Hmm.
Maybe we're not going...
Mm, mm, mm, mm.
All the townspeople's
tax dollars
wasted on a ball, and for what?
For you to make
a complete fool out of me?
To teach me a lesson?
I'm sorry, Father.
You are single-handedly
destroying my legacy.
I know you might not
understand this,
but the woman I chose
didn't choose me.
Oh, I'm sorry, darling.
Aw.
Have you lost your mind?!
You are the future king,
and as king, it is all about you
and your power.
There are no other opinions.
None.
Is this a good time to ask
why we are spending money
on catapults
when we have so many already?
It really just benefits
the catapult makers.
Quiet, Gwen!
I really think we just need
to get some sleep.
No one asked you, Beatrice.
Your time is up, Robert.
You will marry Princess Laura
by week's end.
I don't care
if you don't love each other.
So says the king.
If the crown demands it...
milord.
Darling.
What?
Did you really just say
you don't care
if they love each other?
Yeah. I want the sea monster.
What? Bea-Bea-Beatrice,
don't be...
Ay... ay, ay, ay.
- Your Highness.
- Yes?
- Where'd you find that?
- It's the girl's.
She threw it at my head.
I'm lucky to be alive.
Look at our girl.
Been up all night working.
- She's betting on herself.
- I couldn't do it.
I would've married the prince.
You think the prince
would've picked you?
Cuddly, cute, good at waving.
I mean, come on.
I can hear you.
I bet you're arguing about why
I didn't just say yes
to marrying Robert.
Especially since I'm maybe
in love with him.
Love? It was one night.
I never felt what I felt
last night before.
I mean, you guys,
he's so handsome.
- Oh, yes, he is incredibly handsome.
- Absolutely.
- Annoyingly handsome.
- The cheekbones.
And he likes me for me.
Sounds like true love
to this mouse.
You're right, my friend.
But if saying yes to him
means saying no to this...
...I can't do it.
All right, guys?
I have to try and make a life
for myself, by myself.
Because that is what I want.
And Queen Tatiana is my chance.
Right.
Who's Queen Tatiana?
Cinderella, are you down there?
- Stepmother?
- Dear God, no.
- She scares me.
- Me, too.
- Hello.
- I'm waiting for my tea.
Cinderella.
Oh, I'm coming down.
I'm sick.
Uh-huh.
Well, you didn't miss much
at the ball.
The prince was fixated
on some mystery girl.
Then she ran away like a twit.
So now he's to marry
Princess Laura of Northphalia
the day after next.
Malvolia and Narissa,
they never stood a chance.
And I was so foolish
to believe differently.
A mother just gets carried away.
I know I've been hard on you.
It's not fueled by spite.
I've never shared this
with anyone before, but...
I used to play piano.
Taught myself.
And I was good.
I was really good.
Nothing made me happier.
Then one day,
I was given the opportunity
to train at the finest
school of music,
and I took it.
There I was...
two children, a loving husband,
and I had the audacity
to want more.
It was just a month... one month.
And yet, when I returned,
my husband, well...
...he believed real wives
didn't act so frivolously.
You may think me cruel.
But the real cruelty would be
for me to allow you to think
that you can be
something you can't.
This shoe.
It was you.
Cinderella.
I don't know how you did
what you did last night,
but the prince chose you.
He loves you.
Marry him, and all of
our problems will be solved.
I can't. I told him
I didn't want to marry him.
Tell him you were wrong.
Tell him... tell him
it's all you want.
If not for yourself,
then-then do it for us.
For your family.
I can help our family,
Stepmother.
I can provide for us.
Don't be so stupid.
Who taught you
to think that way?
Please, Cinderella, don't
throw away this opportunity.
Go back to him.
It's too late.
He's marrying someone else.
It's over.
Fine.
Then I'm taking you to Thomas,
and I'm giving you to him today.
I would rather die.
♪ I don't care ♪
♪ This is life ♪
♪ It's not fair ♪
♪ It's not right ♪
♪ All that hope ♪
♪ And that pride ♪
♪ It's a waste ♪
♪ It's a lie ♪
♪ All you want is to breathe ♪
♪ Little girls should run free ♪
♪ But your corset's too tight ♪
♪ And your heels are too high ♪
♪ This treasure you found,
bury it ♪
♪ The only way out, marry it ♪
♪ That shadow of doubt,
carry it ♪
♪ Carry it down
to your grave, oh ♪
♪ The world doesn't need ♪
♪ Another dream girl ♪
♪ You're too dumb ♪
♪ You're too young ♪
♪ Full of heart ♪
♪ So naive ♪
♪ You're so blind ♪
♪ You're so green ♪
♪ You'll give up ♪
♪ Just like me, oh ♪
♪ The wings are ornamental ♪
♪ They have no intention
of letting you fly ♪
♪ Don't be sentimental ♪
♪ Some legends are born
in the wrong time ♪
- ♪ This treasure you found ♪
- ♪ Bury it ♪
- ♪ The only way out ♪
- ♪ Marry it ♪
- ♪ That shadow of doubt ♪
- ♪ Carry it ♪
♪ Carry it down to your grave ♪
♪ Bury it ♪
♪ Marry it ♪
♪ Carry it ♪
♪ Carry it down to your grave ♪
- ♪ Bury it, marry it ♪
- ♪ Your grave ♪
- ♪ Carry it, oh ♪
- ♪ Bury it ♪
- ♪ Marry it ♪
- ♪ Carry it, oh ♪
- ♪ Carry it ♪
- ♪ Bury it, marry it ♪
- ♪ No, no, no, no ♪
- ♪ Carry it, oh ♪
- ♪ No ♪
- ♪ Bury it ♪
- ♪ Marry it ♪
- ♪ Carry it, oh ♪
- ♪ Carry it ♪
♪ Bury it, marry it,
carry it, carry it ♪ - ♪ Oh... ♪
♪ Carry it down to your grave ♪
♪ Your grave, your grave... ♪
♪ The world doesn't need ♪
♪ Another dream girl. ♪
Leave us.
You haven't spoken to me
since last night.
You're mad
because I yelled at you.
I hate to break it to you,
but kings yell.
Please, say something.
You're making me
wildly uncomfortable.
Have you ever wondered
why Robert makes
the process to marry
so difficult?
Because he's a spoiled child
who refuses to grow up. Simple.
I believe it's because of the
example set before him by us.
A marriage without love,
without respect.
Bea, please,
you know I love you.
Saying "love" and showing love
are two very different things,
Rowan.
Before you were king,
I felt your love every day.
You couldn't stand to be away
from me, even for a moment.
Remember, you used to appear
at my window
like a knight in shining armor
and you'd serenade me
with your skull-splitting voice.
We were young.
Things... change.
No. You changed.
The crown changed you.
You're so worried
to look a fool.
So obsessed with your
reputation, with your legacy.
Well, it's only my life's work.
It causes me
a great deal of stress.
Do you think you're the only
person who feels stress?
God, try being your bloody wife.
It is utterly exhausting to sit
next to you and just smile
as if I were nothing more
than a prop,
my voice completely silenced.
I mean, what I wouldn't give
to say, "You're wrong,"
in front of the entire kingdom.
Bea...
you're being unreasonable now.
Well, if you say so.
After all, you're the king.
Can't be any other opinions
other than yours.
Do you know,
there's never a guarantee
with a couple in our position.
But we had love, Rowan.
We had it.
And now...
Robert's wiser than both of us.
Hello.
I'm ready.
You summoned me, Your Highness?
We can't have
a regular conversation
like a normal father and son,
can we?
No, no.
To satisfy your power trip,
you have to sit there
on your slightly too tall
throne.
You-you belittle me in your...
your-your king voice, yes.
All because you're so insecure
with your legacy that you
have to control my every move.
Now, I ask you,
does that sound
like a strong leader to you?
Robert...
I was wrong.
I, King Rowan...
Am I doing the king voice?
A little bit.
You can't help yourself.
Go find the owner
of this glass slipper.
And if she'll take you back,
then marry her.
Or don't.
It's your life, son.
Wh-Why the sudden
change of heart?
Well, definitely
wasn't your mum.
Go on, leave now.
Be bold.
♪ Hear ye, hear ye, hear ye ♪
♪ If you don't know yet,
you won't believe ♪
♪ What I'm about to tell ♪
♪ But our handsome young prince
at the ball ♪
♪ Well, he fell
for a pretty young lady ♪
♪ I hear quite the stunner,
who then turned out to be ♪
♪ Uh-huh, quite the runner,
see, at the end of the night ♪
♪ This woman split so fast,
she left no name ♪
♪ No I.D.,
just a shoe made of glass ♪
♪ And now he's looking
for the girl ♪
♪ With the other glass slipper,
no buckles, no laces ♪
- ♪ Not even a zipper ♪
- ♪ The shoe ♪
♪ The shoe,
does it look like this? ♪
♪ That's a dirty old boot, lady,
swing and a miss ♪
♪ It's hard for me to tell,
could my foot be right? ♪
♪ Your foot's the size of
a canoe, ma'am, way too tight ♪
♪ How unfortunate for me
that I birthed ♪
♪ Ten sons... ♪
Mm.
That is too bad.
But I like those vocal runs.
♪ 'Ey, 'ey, 'ey ♪
♪ People, look, it ain't me
who needs convincing ♪
♪ I ain't the one
with the ring-a-ding-ding ♪
♪ Go home, get your girls
in the shoe that goes bling ♪
♪ And don't show it to me,
tell it to your future king. ♪
Not her.
Worth a try.
No.
I mean, don't they know
I'm looking for her?
No.
Nope, not her.
Nope.
Nope. No. No.
Not interested.
I mean, me, neither.
You don't say.
We're not going to find her.
- We should just go home.
- I can't.
I have to let her know
that it's possible between us.
It's a beautiful thing
how much you love her.
- You crying, Hench?
- So what if I am?
Would that we all have
what Robert has.
I mean, what is life
if you're not with
the person you love?
Right?
Otherwise, we might as well
just close our eyes
and take the ol' mud nap,
because...
nothing else matters.
So we find her, then.
Robert, where did you see her
the last time
you went searching?
I am the king's idiot son.
Hyah!
Cinderella's been
working on her recipes for you.
Well, I should hope so.
♪ If it's a million to one... ♪
Two, three.
For Ella...!
Remember me as a hero!
♪ If it's a million to one ♪
♪ I wanna taste love and pain ♪
♪ Oh, if it's
a shot in the dark ♪
♪ Oh, I wanna feel
pride and shame ♪
♪ Oh, 'cause I, I just can't ♪
- ♪ Afford to be wrong ♪
- ♪ Don't wanna take my time ♪
- ♪ Don't wanna waste one life ♪
- ♪ Even when I'm afraid ♪
♪ It could've been me ♪
♪ You're gonna know my name ♪
♪ Don't wanna live
as an untold story ♪
♪ You're gonna know my ♪
- ♪ You're gonna know my name ♪
- ♪ Oh ♪
♪ Rather go out
in a blaze of glory ♪
♪ You're gonna know my... ♪
♪ Whoa, my... ♪
You all right?
Oh, hey.
- What are you doing here?
- Are you hurt?
No, I-I'm fine.
I just really have to...
Good. I've been looking for you.
Why?
I have something
that I want to say.
You inspired me.
Me?
It never occurred to me
that I could choose
the course of my own life.
See, I-I always felt
that it was written for me.
But watching you, I-I realized
that anything is possible.
That's so sweet.
I'm just really in a hurry.
If we could talk about it...
I realize now that I can have
a life that is all mine.
Great. This is gonna
be a lengthy discussion.
What I'm trying to say
is that I choose me.
Hmm?
God, this is not coming out
how I wanted it to.
I don't have to be king.
It is not what I want anymore.
You are.
So, what I'm saying is
choosing me is choosing us.
That is, as long as
you feel the same way.
Your silence is...
That was the most romantic
moment of my life.
Same.
- I mean, you rode up on a horse.
- I did.
It was really cool.
You look so beautiful.
- You look so handsome.
- Thank you.
Oh, uh, got to go.
I need you to
put me on that horse and get me
to the market square, please.
- Okay.
- What? No.
- No? Okay. I'm sorry. Yes.
- I can walk. It's-it's faster.
But thank you.
That's really nice.
Beatrice!
What fresh hell is this?
It is I, your knight
in shining armor.
You can't be serious.
Darling, suspend
what you know to be true.
Just...
Just-just go with it.
Oh, no. He's gonna sing.
♪ This is me showing you ♪
♪ That I love you ♪
♪ Like I used to ♪
You really don't
have to do this.
But I do, darling.
This is exactly what you wanted.
Nope. No. Not really.
♪ You are more important ♪
♪ Than any sea monster to me ♪
Everybody.
♪ We made babies ♪
- ♪ Together ♪
- ♪ We made babies together ♪
Oh, my God.
♪ I love you... ♪ Okay,
that's enough. That's enough.
Yes. Thank you.
Oh. Big finish.
♪ I'm so sorry ♪
♪ I acted like a ♪
♪ Unbelievably ♪
♪ Pigheaded ♪
♪ Numbskull ♪
- ♪ Numbskull ♪
♪ Numbskull. ♪
Oh, my love.
Oh. Can I come up?
Yes, if you can get
your armor off.
Pack your bags.
Huh?
Huzzah!
Yes!
- Mother? Father?
- In here,
being immortalized.
There's someone
I would like you to meet.
- I'm Ella.
- Now, how lovely.
Yes.
Oh, yeah, I remember you.
You're the statue girl.
That wasn't me.
Yes, it was.
I'm good with faces.
So, do I have
a wedding to prepare?
I mean, no pressure,
but there's an absurd amount
of pastries
left over from that ball.
No, no, we're not in a rush
to get married.
Uh, instead, we're going to
travel the world together.
Ah. Hmm.
I'm sorry if
my decision disrupts
- your plans for succession.
- Well, that's all right.
It just so happens I share blood
with another who, one day,
will be the greatest leader
the realm has ever known.
Hear that, Gwen?
What's happening?
Gwen, my darling girl.
I hereby place you first in line
to inherit the crown, hmm?
Don't stab me in my sleep.
I... shall be king?
Eh, queen.
I'll take it.
Good.
Just so we're clear,
I'm going to rule the land?
- Yes.
- Okay.
And everyone heard that?
- We did. Yes.
- Yes. - Yeah. Mm-hmm.
Oh!
So many ideas!
Like... Oh, I don't know
where to begin!
Oh, good.
Can I take this crown off?
- Yes.
- Shall we have some tea?
It is my honor
to guide this kingdom forward
into a new era.
And to pay my deepest respects
to my brother,
Prince Robert, and his new...
What are we calling you?
Well...
I mean, we don't have to put
a label on it.
Just... in love?
I don't know.
In love?
Yeah.
In love.
And his new love, Ella!
Ella.
I believe this belongs to you.
My mother's brooch.
I thought it could inspire you
on your voyage.
Thank you.
All right, that's enough mirth.
Celebration's over.
Everyone, go home.
- Oh, man.
- Back to work.
- Come on. Let's go.
- No!
You're wrong!
♪ Let's get loud... ♪
♪ Let's get loud,
let's get loud ♪
♪ Turn the music up,
let's do it ♪
♪ Come on, people,
let's get loud ♪
- ♪ Yes, let's get loud ♪
- ♪ Let's get loud ♪
♪ Turn the music up
to hear that sound ♪
♪ Let's get loud ♪
♪ Let's get loud,
let's get loud ♪
- ♪ Whoo! ♪
- ♪ Ain't nobody gotta tell ya ♪
♪ What you gotta do ♪
♪ If you wanna live your life,
live it all the way ♪
♪ And don't you waste it ♪
♪ Don't you waste it,
no, no, no ♪
♪ Every feelin', every beat
can be so very sweet ♪
- ♪ You gotta taste it ♪
- ♪ Taste it ♪
- ♪ You gotta do it ♪
♪ You gotta do it,
gotta do it your way ♪
- ♪ Yeah ♪
- ♪ You gotta prove it ♪
♪ And don't you let nobody
lead you astray ♪
- ♪ You gotta prove it ♪
♪ Gotta mean what you say ♪
♪ Like da da-da-da-da da da ♪
♪ Life's a party, make it hot ♪
♪ Dance, don't ever stop,
whatever rhythm ♪
♪ Every minute, every day,
they ain't here to stay ♪
♪ You gotta live 'em, yeah ♪
- ♪ You gotta do it ♪
♪ You gotta be bold,
you gotta be wiser ♪
♪ You got to prove it ♪
♪ You gotta be tough,
you gotta be stronger ♪
♪ You gotta mean it ♪
♪ Whoo, like ♪
♪ Da-da-da, oh ♪
♪ Let's get loud ♪
♪ No, no, no, yeah ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Let's get loud ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Like da da-da-da-da da ♪
♪ Life is meant to be fun ♪
♪ You're not hurting anyone ♪
♪ Nobody loses ♪
♪ Let the music make you free ♪
♪ Be what you wanna be ♪
♪ Make no excuses ♪
♪ No, you gotta do it ♪
♪ Gotta do it,
gotta do it your way ♪
♪ You've gotta mean it ♪
♪ Gotta mean it,
gotta mean what you say ♪
♪ And don't you let nobody
lead you astray ♪
♪ I know I won't ♪
♪ I know you won't ♪
- ♪ No ♪
♪ So... ♪
♪ So ♪
♪ Let's get loud ♪
♪ Oh... ♪
♪ Let's get, get loud ♪
♪ Loud, loud ♪
♪ Loud, oh ♪
♪ Let's get down ♪
♪ Let's get loud,
let's get loud ♪
- ♪ Let's get loud ♪
- ♪ Oh, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Let's get down,
let's get loud ♪
♪ Let's get loud... ♪
♪ Oh, let's get loud,
let's get loud ♪
- ♪ Get loud ♪
- ♪ Turn the music up ♪
- ♪ To hear that sound ♪
- ♪ That sound ♪
♪ Let's get loud ♪
- ♪ Hey ♪
- ♪ Let's get loud ♪
♪ Ain't nobody gotta tell ya ♪
♪ What you gotta do ♪
♪ Like da da-da-da-da da da ♪
♪ Let's get loud ♪
- ♪ Let's get loud ♪
- ♪ La-la-la, la-la-la ♪
- ♪ La-la ♪
- ♪ Let's get loud ♪
♪ Let's get loud ♪
♪ All I know, all I know ♪
♪ Love will save ♪
♪ Love will save the day... ♪
♪ Let's get loud ♪
♪ Let's get loud... ♪
And so we've reached
the end of this fairy tale.
Our girl lived
happily ever after,
and everybody knew her name.
Ella.
The girl's name is Ella, y'all.
Get it right.
♪ Let's get loud ♪
♪ Let's get loud. ♪
♪ Here I go again ♪
♪ I'm imagining
a world outside ♪
♪ Unlike the one I'm in ♪
♪ Daydreaming again ♪
♪ Of when I'll get a chance ♪
♪ There's a world
that understands ♪
♪ Where you don't hear
the whispers ♪
♪ In the room
you're walking in ♪
♪ Daydreaming again ♪
♪ All I need is a chance ♪
♪ When I feel my fear
staring at me ♪
♪ I tell it just wait and see ♪
♪ I know who I'm gonna be,
I know who I'm gonna be ♪
♪ The world's half asleep ♪
♪ It's gonna wake up and see ♪
♪ If it's a million to one ♪
♪ I'm gonna be that one ♪
♪ And if it's
a shot in the dark ♪
♪ I'm gonna be the sun ♪
♪ And I just can't
afford to be wrong ♪
♪ Even when I'm afraid ♪
♪ You're gonna know my name ♪
♪ Yeah, you're gonna
know my name ♪
♪ I can barely sleep ♪
♪ 'Cause my heart
is always racing ♪
♪ Chasing, pacing
round the room ♪
♪ Living carefully is
something I don't wanna do ♪
♪ When I feel my fear
staring at me ♪
♪ I tell it just wait and see ♪
♪ I know who I'm gonna be,
I know who I'm gonna be ♪
♪ The world's half asleep ♪
♪ It's gonna wake up and see ♪
♪ If it's a million to one ♪
♪ I'm gonna be that one ♪
♪ And if it's
a shot in the dark ♪
♪ I'm gonna be the sun ♪
♪ And I just can't
afford to be wrong ♪
♪ Even when I'm afraid ♪
♪ You're gonna know my name ♪
♪ Yeah, you're gonna
know my name ♪
♪ And I can see her
now and then ♪
♪ The one I know
that I could be ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ I see her laughin' ♪
♪ 'Cause she knew
all along in her head ♪
♪ So when the light
is hard to see ♪
♪ She's telling me ♪
♪ If it's a million to one ♪
♪ I'm gonna be that one ♪
♪ And if it's
a shot in the dark ♪
♪ I'm gonna be the sun ♪
♪ And I, I just can't
afford to be wrong ♪
♪ Even when I'm afraid ♪
♪ You're gonna know my name ♪
♪ You're gonna know
my name ♪
♪ You're gonna know my name ♪
♪ You're gonna know
my name, yeah ♪
♪ You're gonna know my name ♪
♪ You're gonna know
my name. ♪
Okay, okay, dang.